<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>His Maiesties demands to the honourable House of Parliament also certaine intelligences from Windsore, Marlborough, Bathe touching the execution of the militia with their number of trained bands and voluntiers under the command of Captaine Digges and Captaine Daniell : the unlawfull commission of aray executed by the Marques of Hartford and the Lord Seymor : with the rude behaviour of the caveliers : also the Parliaments declaration.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18979</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12297969</idno>
  <idno type="VID">197376</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240988458</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C2296</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12297969</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18979)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 197376)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 246:E108, no 13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>His Maiesties demands to the honourable House of Parliament also certaine intelligences from Windsore, Marlborough, Bathe touching the execution of the militia with their number of trained bands and voluntiers under the command of Captaine Digges and Captaine Daniell : the unlawfull commission of aray executed by the Marques of Hartford and the Lord Seymor : with the rude behaviour of the caveliers : also the Parliaments declaration.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Iohn Iohnson,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Lond. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>July 28, 1642.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Thomason Collection, British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Somerset, William Seymour, --  Duke of, 1588-1660.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Royalists --  Great Britain --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:197376:1"/>
            <p>HIS MAIESTIES Demands to the honourable House of PARLIAMENT, Also Certaine Intelligences From
<list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Windsore,</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Marlborough,</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Bathe.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>TOUCHING The execution of the <hi>Militia.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>With their number of trained Bands and vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luntiers under the command of Captaine <hi>Digges</hi> and Captaine <hi>Daniell.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The unlawfull Commission of Aray, executed by the Marques of <hi>Hartford</hi> and the Lord <hi>Seymor.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>With the rude behaveour of the Caveliers.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>Also the Parliaments Declaration.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Iohn Browne Cler. Parl.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>Lond. Printed for</hi> Iohn Ionson. <hi>Iuly</hi> 28. 1642.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:197376:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:197376:2"/>
            <head>From <hi>Marleborough.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>ON the eighteenth day of this present moneth of <hi>Iuly,</hi> the <hi>Militia</hi> was put in execution at which place there met four hundred foot compleatly armed, under the command of Captain <hi>Diggs,</hi> Captain <hi>Daniel,</hi> and others, about an hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Voluntiers from the Town of <hi>Marlborough,</hi> these men have made gallant expressions of their in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentions to spend their lives and fortunes in the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of the King and Parliament, at <hi>Skipnam</hi> there is this day expected six hundred Foot, besides divers Voluntiers, the Lord Marques <hi>Hartford</hi> and the Lord <hi>Seymor</hi> are every day expected at <hi>Marlborough,</hi> to put the Commission of Aray in execution.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <head>From <hi>Windsor.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>ABout some few dayes past there were some five Cavaliers that came into <hi>Windsor</hi> Forest to kill some of his Majesties Deer, and having gained a fit stand, took the oportunity of the next approaching Ga<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e, which were two lovely Stagges, the Cavalier
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:197376:3"/> that was to shoot indeavoured so to place them in his eye, that he might send a mortall wound to them both, and having shot like a good markes man, made good his determination, upon the discharge, the rest of the company came in with chearfull coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenances to the fall of the Deer, endeavouring with all celerity to carry these Stagges away without a discovery, but their care and industry could not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent their ensuing danger, the Foresters having <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eard the report of the Piece hasted to the place from whence the sound came, where they found these Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>valiers busie about their stollen pleasures, the Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>resters being all well armed martialled themselves in in such aray as they might best encounter with these Cavaliers that had been the destruction of their game, no sooner had they observed the approaching danger, by way of Fortification each Gentleman placed his Horse before him as a Bulwarke to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend their Bodies, and having laid their Pieces upon their Horses, gave fire and sent a volley of shot a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst the Foresters, the sight was for a while very hot, yet with little losse of blood, but the continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of it made the Cavaliers spend most of their shot and powder, one of them flying was pursued by a Forester, and forced to deliver his Armes, the rest of the Gentlemen upon a fair treaty had liberty to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part, leaving behinde them their Stagges. Much troubled were they at the consideration of their ill fortunes, and thereupon entred into a deep con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sultation how they might be revenged on the Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>resters, having laid their Plot, their next thoughts
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:197376:3"/> were the putting of it in execution, in the first place they made inquiry for the Forester that had seised on the Gun, and being advertised that he was at a neighbouring Alehouse, they entred the house, seis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed on the Keeper, each man laying hold upon a part of him, insomuch as the miserable Keeper thought his limbes should be torne from his body, having haled him up and down, and putting him into a piti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full fright, they would not free him from the pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishment they intended, till he had paid whatsoever expences they should then be at, and returne them their Gun with one of their Stagges, so much was the poor Forester tormented, that he willingly condiscended to their desires after they had received their Stagge, and taken the benefit of his sees, they departed each man to his severall habitation, where they feasted themselves with fat Venison, not long after one of the Cavaliers were taken and awarded to go to prison, but so well was he beloved of the Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>male sex, that thirty Amazonian spirits rescued the Prisoner, the conductors presently fled from the fury of these malignant spirits, the prisoner presently hasted to some place of safety, and though the Sheriffe of the same County was then present, and gave order to a Trained Band that was then in rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinesse to stay him, yet such was his nimblenesse, that hee passed through the severall rankes of the Souldiers and escaped. Such was the activenes that the by-standers imagined he had long conversed amongst those wilde creatures of the Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rest, and that he was transformed into the nature of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:197376:4"/> them. It were to be wished, that such Cavaliers as these that will not be kept within the compasse of the Law might suddenly feel the scourge thereof, lest these extravagant courses makes others (that are bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter minded) follow their bad examples, and pillage houses.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <head>From <hi>Bath.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Inhabitants of the Citie of <hi>Bath</hi> expresse their great greifes in that they have had little Company this Summer, they fear that their chief <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>enefactours bends towards the North, and that cold Climate makes them thinke the lesse of Bathing, for having had recourse to the waters of <hi>Knavesbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough</hi> their heat is allayed, the poor Guides are now necessitated to guide one another from the Alehouse, least they should loose their practise, the Ladies that are there are fallen into a Lethargie for want of stir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring Cavaliers to keep them awake, were it not for these Nymphes the waters would lose their vertue, <hi>Pluto</hi>'s cauldron had never lesse purboyled flesh in it to please the palate of his Courtiers, the poor Fid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers are ready to hang themselves in their stringes for a pastime, for want of other imployments.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:197376:4"/>
            <head>Propositions and demands of the King in his Answer to the late Petition of both Houses of Parliament.</head>
            <p n="1">1. THat the money gathered be not imployed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst him, but for the relief of <hi>Ireland, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. That his Town of <hi>Hull</hi> be delivered up to him and then he will pardon all persons that have offend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. That the Navie be forthwith resigned and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered into such hands as he hath directed, decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring it high Treason in the Commanders of those Ships so detained from him.</p>
            <p n="4">4. That his Parliament <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> adjourned and remo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved from <hi>London</hi> to a place more secure and safe for his Person, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb facs="tcp:197376:5"/>
            <head>The Parliaments Declaration.</head>
            <p>THe Lords and Commons do declare, that a Garrison of Souldiers is at <hi>Newcastle,</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the command of the Earle of <hi>Newcastle:</hi> Likewise Earle <hi>Rivers</hi> being put into the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission of Aray, exercises it with much rigour, imprisoning all those that oppose him.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Ordered that this be printed and published. <hi>Iohn Brown Cler. Parl.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>